Guide to the Stanford University Film Collection SC1032
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Films
  - Careers in Banking. B version., unknown; E 121; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 29.5 min
    "on leader: "B version - continuous - no quiz" part of Krumboltz's papers SC 219 sponsor: California Bankers Association"
    Krumboltz, John D.
  - Careers in Banking. A version., unknown; E 122; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 33 min
    "For use with workbooks part of Krumboltz's papers SC 219 sponsor: California Bankers Association"
  - Careers in Banking. C version., unknown; F 123; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 44 min
    ""Problems for each section appear in titles on screen." part of Krumboltz's papers SC 219 sponsor: California Bankers Association"
  - Cal vs Stanford, 1946; B 124; unknown
    Creator: unknown
    Unable to open can to determine film size and number of reels
  - Stanford: A Place in History, unknown; D 125; 4 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Creator: Panorama Productions [name on can]
    Did not view - no notations on headers; presumably mutliple copies of same thing
    Stanford University
  - Stanford: A Place in History, unknown; C 125.5; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 17:35
    Did not view
  - Modern Business Machines, 1947; E 126; 2 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Creator: Teaching Aids Exchange and Cletus E. Zumwalt
    Part of thesis by Cletus E. Zumwalt (1948)
  - Notes on a visit to Stanford, 1981; B 127; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 8 min
    Creator: Dean L. Wetherell, Dept. of Communications
    Visit of Congressman Anderson to SU in 1981. Transferred from Green-Media 3/5/2003.
    Anderson, John
  - California art for peace, 1970; B 128; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 13 min
    Creator: Kirk Varnedoe
    SU and Berkeley art students and the traveling exhibit "California Art for Peace." Transferred from Green-Media 3/5/2003.
  - Homage to Rodin, 1968; D 129; 2 film reel(s) (16mm); 19
    Creator: Pyramid Films; Herb Golden, writer & director
    Works from B. Gerald Cantor Art Foundation; filmed during exhibit "Homage to Rodin" at LA County Musuem of Art. Transferred from Green-Media 03/35/2003.
  - Martin Luther King, Jr. at Stanford University, 1967; F 130; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Scope and Contents
    Film documents a speech given by Martin Luther King at Stanford University on April 14, 1967 about racism and civil rights in American society. Dr. King contends that there are "two Americas": one "beautiful" and the "other America, " which is an "arena of blasted hopes and dreams." He goes on to explain that "we are seeking to make America one nation."
    African Americans -- Civil rights -- United States.; King, Martin Luther; Stanford University; King, Martin Luther, Jr.
  - Track meet at Stanford [possibly with USC], 1929; A 131; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Creator: unknown (possibly Jos. Sloss)
    Kodak safety film; donor note indicates this one is also USC, but the original box is not so labelled.
    Athletics
  - Stanford - USC track, 1933 May 6; A 132; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Kodak panchromatic safety film
  - Commencement, Frost Amphitheater, 1937; A 133; 1 film reel(s) (8mm); 10 mins.
    Creator: Thorton W. Mitchell
    Video copy on V250 (which also includes other students and campus scenes)
    Commencement; Mitchell, Thorton W.
  - Track and field films and filmstrips, 1936-1977 and undated; 134; 86 filmstrip(s)
  - Rose Bowl parades, 1941, 1946; A 135; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    in color
  - National Centennial Celebration - San Jose, D 136; 2 film reel(s) (16mm)
    "cans labeled "image transform inc."
    centennial
  - National Centennial Los Angeles "Speaking of Stanford", D 137; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    cans labeled "image transform inc."
  - Stanford Hymn Rap, B 138; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 4.5 min
    Creator: Palmer Film & Video Services
  - Stanford "Friday"; also labeled Formal Show Films, B 139; 4 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Creator: peter arnott productions
    possibly for Centennial event. 6 subjects on each: 1. Cornerstone 2. Vow Boys 3. WWII 4. Protest 5. Fame 6. Finale [title is "Dedicated "on 4th reel]
  - Stanford vs. S.F. ball game [football?], 1946; A 140; 1 film reel(s) (8mm)
  - “Behavior Therapy with an Autistic Child”, circa 1960s; F 141; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Created by the Psychology Department with therapist Gerald C. Robinson and discussant Leonard Krasner, and a child.
- Additional Films, Accession ARCH-2014-114
  - Golden Gate Exposition, Stanford campus, etc., circa 1939; ARCH-2014-114; 1 film reel(s) (8mm)
- Additional Films, Accession ARCH-2015-065
  Human rights advocacy; Burres, Bruni; Mehlman, David; Human Rights Watch (Organization); McGuire, Kevin S.
  - Invisible Reign, by Kevin KcGuire, 1992 Oct 26; 1.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Invisible Reign, by Kevin KcGuire, 1992 Oct 26; 1.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Invisible Reign, by Kevin KcGuire, 1992 Oct 26; 1.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Invisible Reign, by Kevin KcGuire, 1992 Oct 26; 1.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Down for Life, by David Mehlman, 1996 Aug 30; 1.5; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Down for Life, by David Mehlman, 1996 Aug 30; 1.6; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Down for Life, by David Mehlman, 1996 Aug 30; 1.7; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Senorita Extraviata - Human Rights Watch International Film Festival, by Bruni Burres, 1998 Jun 5; 1.8; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Senorita Extraviata - Human Rights Watch International Film Festival, by Bruni Burres, 1998 Jun 5; 1.9; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
- Additional Films, Accession ARCH-2016-128
  Films belonged to Samuel Freeman, member of Stanford class of 1935.
  - Dachfour & Empress of France, 1_01; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Farm 1938 - Sit, Monty, Wolf, B, Orvis; Farm 1940 - Russell, Milney, Wolf, Sit, Ginny Jones and friend; Farm 1940 - Russell, Milney; Florida 1940 - Fred Whitney, Wantano, Ginny Jones, cockfight; Farm 1941 - Summer, also departing for Army (January 1942), Lucy High, Russell, Wolf; Farm 1944 - Milney, Jean Noland, 1938-1944; 1_02; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Palo Alto Airport, Train; Stanford "U" A Day at Stanford., 1930s; 1_03; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Point Sal, Picnic, Grandma visit, 1_04; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - S.P.S. Felix, 1930; 1_05; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
    Felix finds Em fickle; Rowing and anniversary pictures at S.P.S., Pete's place; leaving New York, Mary Wallace, Minnewaska.
  - Summer - Toby, Wolf, Fritz, Maxine. Farm., 1931-1932; 1_06; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Tahoe; S.B. Col. film; Johnny; Farm - Dad, 1_07; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Shop (Vogue), Beach (Betty); Arrowhead; San Diego; Stan. Swim, 1_08; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - S.U., 1936; 1_09; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Unlabeled, 1_10; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Farm & Airport, United @ LaGuardia - Russ, Milney, Sam, Wolf, [Punch/], 1951 May; 1_11; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Unlabeled, 1_12; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Unlabeled, 1_13; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Unlabeled, 1_14; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Unlabeled, 1_15; 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
- Additional Film, Accession ARCH-2017-082
  - The Fast Male (Box 1)
- Additional Film, Accession ARCH-2017-105
  - Written on film reel: Foothill - 32; Double Team & Trap Block., 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 1)
- Additional Film, Accession ARCH-2018-129
  - Campus Footage by John Spielman, circa 1928-1929
    Film of campus scenes and football game taken by John Spielman (AB, Civil Engineering, 1922).